Well, hopefully you were able to give
that a try. Let's go over the solution.
All right, so the first thing we need to
do is we need to create a function that
will add items. Write a function that
will read the text user types into the
input box. Use the template tag to
create a copy of the item. Fill in the
items text. Add a click event listener
to the remove button and append the
finished item to the shopping list
container and probably call it create
item. We also want to create a function
called remove shopping list items that
removes an element when we click it. And
we want to connect our
we want to connect our function to our
add button. So let's go ahead and this
last one seems like the easiest one. So
I'm going to do that one first. Um I'm
going to make my create item function.
I'm going to leave it empty and then I'm
going to connect it using the add
button. So if we come over here and come
to script.js JS I'm going to put name
description
shopping list handler. Okay.
So the very first thing I'm going to
come over here. I can see that this add
button is inside of a div with div with
the id of shopping form. So if I want to
add an event listener to this then I
need to be able to find that button. And
so it's a button inside of a div that
has an id of shopping form. So what
we're going to do here is let's write
our function first. So we'll call it
function create item
and we'll leave it empty for now. And
then I'm going to say document.query
selector. And I'm going to look for um
shopping form.
And directly inside of the shopping form
element, I want to find the button. Once
I've done that, I can add event
listener. And the event we're listening
for is a click. And when they click it,
we want to create an item.
Great. So that handles that. Um
well, let's create our item. When we
create the item, um, we know that there
is some placeholder text here, or sorry,
there's some text here that we need to
use. And it looks like we've been
provided a template in the templates.
There's a span where we're going to want
to put the text and a button for
removing the text. So, let's go ahead
and take advantage of this template. And
let's grab um the input tag and get the
value from that. So, the first thing we
want to do is document.query query
selector. If we were in a bigger page,
we could maybe be a little more
specific. Actually, let's be specific.
So, we know that our input is inside of
shopping form
and we'll grab the input
and we'll grab its value
and we'll say let item name equal the
value that we just grabbed. So now that
we've got the value, now we need to
create a new element using that
template. So if we want to use that
template, we first have to grab that
template. So we'll say let template
equal document query selector and look
for the template tag.
Then we need to import it so that we can
actually use the HTML inside of the
template tag. So, we'll say let my new
item equal
um document dot import node. We want to
import the templates content.
And we want all of the content, not just
the first layer. So, we're going to put
true.
Now, we need to set the text. So, we'll
say my new item doquery selector. And in
here we are going to look for do item
text I believe. Let's look. Um item text
is the class. So we're going to use
that. And then the button is remove
button. So we'll look for the item text
and we'll set its inner text equal to
the item name that we just got back.
The other thing we want to do is we want
this function to be able to remove
itself or we want this item to be able
to be removed if we click the remove
button.
Um, and if we want to do that then we
need to have a function for it. So I'm
going to say function remove shopping
list item
and we need to attach it. So I'm going
to access my item. I'm going to query
select for the remove button
and then I'm going to add an event
listener. When they click it, I want to
call remove shopping list item.
So, so far I will have set that to be
something and set that to be something
and they're all inside of a list item.
This is all fine and dandy, but I
haven't actually added them to the page
yet. So let's add them to the page. Um
we'll say document.query selector.
And if we look on the page, our ul has
an ID of shopping list. So we'll say
shopping
list dot append child. And the child we
want to append is my new item.
So we've already added create item to
our button. Let's go make sure that this
is working.
So, we'll come to our shopping list and
we'll say apples.
And tada, apples showed up. When we
click the remove, nothing happens. But
that's expected. We haven't written
anything in the remove function yet. Um,
but let's add pairs.
And then the I'm not going to try and
spell bananas off the top of my head on
live camera. I will do that later. Okay.
So, if I click this remove for pairs, I
want to remove pairs. How do I know
which one of these I'm clicking? Well, I
could probably use the event handler
object to figure it out. So, let's
accept the event as E.
And here, um, I'm just going to
console.log E.
So, let's add apples add. Let's inspect
the page.
Um, and we'll click remove. We get our
pointer event.
We get that the target is the button.
Well, we wanted the target. The thing we
want to delete is actually the whole
item. And while there are easier ways to
do this, I realized that in previous
videos, I did not teach them. So, we're
going to do this the little more
difficult way. The way that I did teach
in the previous videos. We remember that
if we click an item and a surrounding
parent item has an event handler that
listens to the exact same thing, it
bubbles up. So, it first handles this
event and then it handles this event and
we can take advantage of this um in our
in our code. So, let's come over here.
So, if they click it, the first thing we
want to do is we want to add another
event listener
onto our item. And where do we want to
target? We're actually going to target
this list item. So, we're going to do um
query selector with list item add event
listener click remove the shopping list
item.
So, it's going to call both of these are
going to call the same function.
In our function, we're going to see if
e.target
get attribute
class
is
remove
button. Sorry, I was thinking of set
attribute. Um, and I got a little bit
distracted and started typing and got
and then realized I was doing something
very wrong. So what we're saying is what
we want to say is if the if
e.target.gatt Get attribute class
is
remove
button
and
the current target attribute class
is not equal to
remove button
then we want to say e.current target.re
and that will remove it. So what are we
doing here? What we're doing is we're
saying find the thing that was clicked,
get its attribute, get its class
attribute. If it's remove button, then
they must have clicked the remove
button. And so therefore, we do actually
want to do something probably.
Now remember, there are two event
handlers here. The one that is on the
button and the one that is on the list
item.
So two event handlers are going to call
this function. And we are saying if the
current event handler is on the list
item, then we want to remove the list
item. If it's not on the list item,
meaning it's on the remove button, then
we don't want to remove the button cuz
we want to remove the entire list item.
So, we'll then remove the entire list
item. So, we'll save this. We'll come
over here and we'll say bananas. B A N A
N A S.
and apples
and pears.
And then if we remove apples, it
vanishes. So that's all great, but we
would like to clear this input when we
create a new item. So what I'm going to
do here is I'm going to say
document.query selector,
and I'm going to copy this query
selector from up here.
And I'm going to set its value equal to
nothing.
So if we save that when we come over we
can say apples and it adds them and we
can remove them and we are done.
Thanks for watching.